Guide to the Tillie Olsen Papers, 1930-1990 M0667
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 3. Correspondence
  - Subseries E. Correspondence: Publishers/Requests
    - Labor Defender (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - League of American Writers (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Lippincott (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Macmillan Company (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Maxim Lieber (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Modern Quarterly (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - New Masses (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - New Quarterly (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - New Republic (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Partisan Review (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Peninsula (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Random House (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Reynal and Hitchcock, Inc. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Robert M. McBride & Co. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Russell & Volkening, Inc. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Scribner's (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Simon & Schuster (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Texas Quarterly (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Ticknor & Fields (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Vanguard (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Virago (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Virago (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Young Worker (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous publishers/agents (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous publishers/agents (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Corr. with foreign publishers (with outgoing) (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Corr. with foreign publishers (with outgoing) (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Tell Me A Riddle: anthologies, re-publications (letters and forms) (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Tell Me A Riddle: anthologies, re-publications (letters and forms) (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Corr. re. reprinting of "1 Out of 12" (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - REQUESTS: Blurbs by Tillie Olsen (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - REQUESTS: Blurbs by Tillie Olsen (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - REQUESTS: Blurbs by Tillie Olsen (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Requests for Blurbs (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Requests for Blurbs (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Corr.: requests for blurbs, appearances, recommendations (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Corr.: requests for blurbs, appearances, recommendations (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Corr.: requests for blurbs, appearances, recommendations (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Corr.: requests for blurbs, appearances, recommendations (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Responses to requests (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Corr. re. corrections and changes in additions of Silences (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Corr. re. copyright permissions (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Corr. re. permissions/requests for dramatizations/adaptations (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Corr. re. permissions/requests for dramatizations/adaptations (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Corr. re. corrections in foreword to Black Women: Writers at Work (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Permission: Bloodrot, Inc. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - General Requests (interviews, questionnaires, etc) (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - General Requests (interviews, questionnaires, etc) (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - General Requests (interviews, questionnaires, etc) (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Requests to serve as judge on boards, panels, etc. (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Requests for biographical information (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Foreign correspondence (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Foreign correspondence (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Foreign correspondence (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Foreign correspondence, Trevi Publishers (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Foreign correspondence, China (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Foreign correspondence, Japan (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Foreign correspondence, Netherlands (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Foreign correspondence, Germany (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Foreign correspondence, England (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Letters of recommendation for fellowships, academic placement, or advancement (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Letters of recommendation for fellowships, academic placement, or advancement (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Letter of recommendation for Tillie Olsen by Janet Harowitz Murray (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence re. recommendations, nominations for grants (with outgoing) (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence re. recommendations, nominations for grants (with outgoing) (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence re. recommendations, nominations for grants (with outgoing) (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Ann Watkins, inc. (Box 33, Folder 1)
- Series 4. Manuscripts by others
  Series IV is entitled "Manuscripts by Others." These are short stories, poems, and articles primarly written by friends of Tillie Olsen which were sent to her for either personal viewing or critical appraisal. Included are poems by Adrienne Rich, Anne Sextant, Scott Turow and short stories by Sandy Boucher, Michele Cliff, and Susan Griffin.
  - Alta: "Song of the Wife, Song of the Mistress" (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Appleton, Sarah: "The Breath of Blessing That Calls Us to Speech: Sentences on Poetry" (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Boucher, Sandy: Miscellaneous short stories, articles, etc. (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Brandon, Dolores: "In Praise of the Common Woman" (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Brodine, Karen: "The Politics of Women Writing" (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Cliff, Michele: "Filaments," "The Garden," "On Claiming an Identity They Taught Me to Despise" (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Cliff, Michele: "Anonymity and the Denial of Self"; book review (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Cooper, Jane: "Nothing has been Used in the Manufacture of This Poetry That Could have been Used in the Manufacture of Bread," "The Children's Ward," "Threads: Rosa Luxemburg from Prison" (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Dodson Le Tourneau, Gayle: poems (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Duncan, Erika: "The Play" (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Dunning, Linda: short stories (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Durham, Flora: poems, "Not Your Usual Rehearsal" (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Earle, Ralph: poems (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Elman, Richard: poems, articles (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Gardinier, Sue: "In Memoriam" (Box 36, Folder 15)
  - Gerson, Deborah: poems (Box 36, Folder 16)
  - Gilbert, Celia: poems (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Goedicke, Patricia: poems (Box 36, Folder 18)
  - Griffin, Susan: poems, short stories (Box 36, Folder 19)
  - Guerard, Albert: "The Vanishing Anarchists: A Memory" (Box 36, Folder 20)
  - Hanna, Gayle: poems, short story, article (Box 36, Folder 21)
  - Hedges, Elaine: "Quilts and Women's Culture" (Box 36, Folder 22)
  - Hughes, Jonathan: "The Jap Camp" (Box 36, Folder 23)
  - Hughes, Mary Gray: poems (Box 36, Folder 24)
  - Janows, Jill: poems (Box 36, Folder 25)
  - Kallet, Marilyn: poems (Box 36, Folder 26)
  - Katzman, Eleanore: "To Frank - From His Clarinet" (Box 36, Folder 27)
  - Kaye, Melanie: poems, journal excerpts (Box 36, Folder 28)
  - Kitrilakis, Thalia: poems (Box 36, Folder 29)
  - Kolodny, Annette: "Dancing Through the Minefield: Some Observations on the Theory, Practice, and Politics of a Feminist Literary Criticism" (Box 36, Folder 30)
  - Krapf, K.: short stories (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Krapf, Norbert: poems (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Kumin, Maxine: poems (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Lazreg, Marnia: "Feminism and Difference: The Perils of Writing as a Woman on Women in Algeria" (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Limmer, Ruth: Introduction to Journey Around My Room (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Mays, Raymina: "Kind of Tender," "Lerna's-Mother-Verda-Lee" (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Meehan, Maude: poems (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Meyer, Howard: articles, short stories (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Meyer, Odette: "The Return of the Secret Jews" (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Minty, Judith: "Letting Go" (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Moers, Ellen: "Mme de Staël and the Woman of Genius" (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Moss, Rose: "Exile" (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Murray, Michele: diary excerpts; biographical articles (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Nason, Thelma: poem, short story (excerpt) (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Ng, Fae Myenne: "pressed petals," "One Hundred and Thrity Four Steps" (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Orr, Elaine: poems, dissertation (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Papanek, Hanna: poem (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Park-Fuller, Linda: production notes (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Phillips, Jayne Anne: short story (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Polite, Frank: poems (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Redman, Blanche: short story, poems (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Rich, Adrienne: poems, articles (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - Rich, Adrienne: poems, articles (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Rosenfelt, Deborah: "Of Love and Bicycling" (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Ruddick, Sally: poem (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - Sarton, May: "The Precious Seed for Donald Gatch" (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Schick, Carla: poems (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Sextant, Anne: poems (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - Shanahan, Thomazine: "Michele Murray 1933-1974" (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - Sternburg, Janet: poems (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Tanenhaus, Beverly: poems (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - Tovish, Margo: poems (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - Turow, Scott: "For the Year of the Insane: a prayer" (Box 37, Folder 33)
  - Ward, Theadora: "Cupboards: A Norwegian Episode" (Box 37, Folder 34)
  - Walker, Alice: "These Days"; article (Box 37, Folder 35)
  - Waterman, Ray: "Internal Triangle" (Box 37, Folder 36)
  - Wong, Nellie: poems (Box 37, Folder 37)
  - Yalom, Marilyn: "'La Chute' and 'A Hero of Our Time'" (Box 37, Folder 38)
  - Yamada, Mitsuye: poems (Box 37, Folder 39)
  - Zucker, Jack: poems (Box 37, Folder 40)
- Series 5. Articles and Papers regarding Tillie Olsen
  Series V consists of articles and papers regarding Tillie Olsen. These are published articles that have appeared in magazines and journals along with student papers that have been sent to Olsen for her evaluation. Also included in this series are clippings from magazines and newspapers reviewing her books, movie adaptations, and public appearances. Finally, to end Series V, there is a section of unrelated papers and articles that Tillie Olsen kept for her own personal records.
  - Subseries 1. Articles re: Tillie Olsen
    - "From the Thirties: Tillie Olsen and the Radical Tradition" - Deborah Rosenfelt (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - "Tillie Olsen: Witness as Servant" - Catherine R. Stimpson (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - "A Voice of One's Own: Contemporary Short Fiction by North American Women" - Ann Harleman (Stewart) (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - "Dare to Write: Virginia Woolf, Tillie Olsen, Gloria Anzaldua" - Carolyn Woodward (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - "Overcoming Silences: Teaching Writing for Women" - Alix Kates Shulman (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - "Silences Unsilenced...Tillie Olsen" - Sara Maitland (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - "Deconstructing the Sexual Politic: Virginia Woolf and Tillie Olsen" - Elizabeth A. Meese (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - "Limning: or Why Tillie Writes" - Ellen Cronan Rose (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - "Creative Experimentation in American Nonfiction Narrative: Mark Twain, W.E.B. DuBois, James Agee and Tillie Olsen" - Shelley Fisher Fishkin (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - "The Riddle of Tillie Olsen" - Elenore Lester (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Introductions to "Tell Me A Riddle" - Cora Kaplan (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - "In the Shadow of the Golden Mountains" - Lis Harris (The New Yorker) (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - "New Light on the Exploitation of Women" - Marilyn Goldberg (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - "These Modern Women: Autobiographical Essays from the Twenties" (Introduction) - Elaine Showalter (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - "Stages of Dissent: Olsen, Grekova, and the Politics of Creativity" - Susan Hardy Aiken "Revolutions from Within" - Ekaterina Stetsenko (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - "Death Labors" - Joanne Trautmann Banks (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - "The Whole Story" - Julia E. Connelly (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - "De-Riddling Tillie Olsen's Writings" - Selma Burkom and Margaret Williams (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - "Reclaiming the Inadvertent: Olsen's Visceral Voice in Yonnondio: From the Thirties" - Barbara Cantalupo (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - "Tillie Olsen: the Voice of the Silenced" - Jill Farinelli (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - "Alternative Responses to Life in Tillie Olsen's Work" - Annette Bennington McElhiney (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - "Tillie Olsen: Storyteller of Working America" - Sally Cunneen (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - "Feminists Look at Motherhood" - Annie Gottlieb (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - "Women Writing in America: On Tillie Olsen" - Blanche M. Gelfant (Box 38, Folder 23)
    - "An Analysis of the Works of Tillie Olsen with Particular Emphasis on the Image of the Mother" - Thesis, by Laura Alper, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 24)
    - "Tillie Olsen" - Hamblem, Abigail Ann (Box 38, Folder 25)
    - "Coming of Age in the Thirties: A Portrait of Tillie Olsen" - Erica Duncan (Box 38, Folder 26)
    - "Tillie Olsen" - Marleen Barr (Box 38, Folder 27)
    - Untitled essay w/ no author (Box 38, Folder 28)
    - "Tillie Olsen: In Mutuality" - Thomazine Shanahan (Box 38, Folder 29)
    - "'I Stand Here Ironing': Motherhood As Experience and Metaphor" - Joanne S. Frye (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - Subseries 2. Student Papers
    - "The Figure of Woman: Artist in Gilman, Woolf, and Olsen" - Rachel Blau DuPlessis (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - "Tillie Olsen: Surviving the Silences" - ? (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - "Tille Olsen: The Witness as Servant" - Catherine R. Stimpson (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - "An Ode to Eva and All Women" - Ann Weinstein (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - "Tillie Olsen, I Stand Here Ironing" - Amy Grunder (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - "What Persists in Loss: A Reading of Tillie Olsen's Yonnondio: From the Thirties" - Barbara White (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - "After Reading Yonnondio: From the Thirties" - Chu Wei Ling (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - "Radical Female: the Politics of the Body and the Mother/Child Relationship in Tillie Olsen's Work" and "Tillie Olsen: The Writer as a Jewish Woman" - Bonnie Lyons (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - "Tillie Olsen: A Comparative Study of Two Works of Fiction and Their Film Adaptations" - Owen (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - "The Struggle for One's Own Truth: Images of War and Peace in Tillie Olsen's Life and Art" - ? (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - "Harnassing the 'Angel in the House' - Thoughts Arising from Silences" - Nancy Priester Karl (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - "Tillie Olsen: 'Still Enough to Live By'" - Carolyn Hagopian (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - "Tillie Olsen: An Overview" - Jessica Warnick (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - "The Jewish Mother Riddle" - Patti Renner-Tana (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Untitled (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - Untitled - Carloyn Rhodes (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Untitled - excerpts (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous/unidentifiable excerpts (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 3. Newsclippings, Magazine articles, etc.
    - Clippings/articles (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - Clippings/articles (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - Clippings/articles (Box 39, Folder 21)
    - Clippings/articles (Box 39, Folder 22)
    - Clippings/articles (Box 39, Folder 23)
    - Clippings/articles (Box 39, Folder 24)
    - Clippings/articles (Box 39, Folder 25)
    - Clippings/articles (Box 39, Folder 26)
    - Clippings/articles (Box 39, Folder 27)
    - Clippings/articles (Box 39, Folder 28)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 39, Folder 29)
    - Miscellaneous reviews (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - clippings/reviews (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - clippings/reviews (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - clippings/reviews (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - clippings/reviews (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - clippings/reviews (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - clippings/reviews, foreign (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - clippings/reviews, foreign (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - clippings/reviews, foreign (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 4. Miscellaneous / Unrelated / Unidentified articles, etc.
    - "Virginia Woolf and her Violin: Mothering, Madness and Music" (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified excerpt (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Paper: Laurie Olsen (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous poems/short stories: unidentified (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - "A la Recherche du Temps Trivial": Gregory Battcock (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Cactus Alley: Student publication, University of Texas, San Antonio (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Unidentified Poems (photocopy) (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - "Knotted Strings" (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - "The Country and the City" (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - "The Friendship of Women" - Anita Barrows (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - "Lesbianism: A Socialist Feminist Perspective" - Susan Williams (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - "Olive Schreiner: Cartographer of the Spirit," book review: Jane Marcus (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - "Auriga, Andromeda, Cameoleopardalis," Howard Griffin (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - "Poetry in the Classroom," Roberts W. French (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - "The Proletarian Revolution and the Problem of Genius" - Deborin; "Science and the Unexpected Universe" - Loren Eisley (Box 41, Folder 17)
- Series 6. Transcripts of interviews and talks, 1963-1982
  Series VI contains transcripts of various interviews and talks given by Tillie Olsen during the years 1963-1982.
  - "Responding to the Nuclear Threat", March 16, 1982 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Interview by Dan Fooler (?) (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Interview by Gerri Lange, Channel 9 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - "An Interview with Tille Olsen and Grace Paley" - Maxine Feifer (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Interview by Joe Cuomo (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Interview (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Interview (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Interview by Aurelie J. Sheehan (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Interview by Peter Marchant, Mary Elsie Robertson (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Interview (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Interview: UND Writers Conference (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Interview by Marilyn Yalom (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - "A Collage of Talks with Tillie Olsen" - Erika Duncan (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Blue Ridge Mountain Films Interview with Tillie Olsen (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Interview by Carol (?) and Elaine (?) (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - "Excerpts from a talk by Tillie Olsen" (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - "Death of the Creative Process" - transcript of a seminar given by Tillie Olsen, Radcliffe Institure for Independent Study, March 15, 1963 (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Address at San Francisco Public Library, Summer 1973 (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - "Reflections" - Emerson College, March 21, 1974 (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - Radcliffe Forum: "Comprehensions,", March 13, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 20)
  - Tillie Olsen Tapes (Writer's Conference) - excerpt (Box 42, Folder 21)
  - "PW Interviews: Tillie Olsen" - Lisa See (Box 42, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous/unidentified excerpts (Box 42, Folder 23)
  - "A Visit with Tillie Olsen" - University of Vermont, October 1972 (Box 42, Folder 24)
  - Meiklejohn Civil Liberties Institute Panel: format (Box 42, Folder 25)
  - Introductions to various Talks (Box 42, Folder 26)
  - Tillie Olsen's notes for talk (Columbia University, 1969 ?) (Box 42, Folder 27)
- Series 7. Teaching materials
  Series VII consists of teaching material and student work during the time Tillie Olsen taught at Amherst, MIT, University of Massachusettes, and Stanford. Class notes, students papers, student journals, and correspondence with the sudents comprise the majority of this series. Also included are folders referring to the Radcliffe Institute, which contains newsletters, pamphlets, and other ephemera regarding the Bunting Institute Society of Fellows.
  - Corr. with students (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - University of Massachusetts class (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - MIT (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - 1972 class journals, Stanford ("Women in Literature") (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - 1972 class journals, Stanford ("Women in Literature") (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Notes on women in literature and film (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Women's films (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - TLO Correspondence @ Stanford: Louise Ritzman, et al (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Stanford teaching: Louise's class, film's shown (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Class lists: Sept., 1969 (Amherst) (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Applications from students (and class reviews) - Stanford (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Stanford: student work (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Stanford: student work (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - "April Smith: 'Women' and 'Solange'" (Box 43, Folder 14)
  - John Zimarowski: "A Women in Literature Journal with a Deluxe Gay Bias" and correspondence (Box 43, Folder 15)
  - Amherst class: photocopied teaching materials (Box 43, Folder 16)
  - Amherst: application letters; class lists (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Amherst, notes (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Amherst, class lists, exams (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Items of interest from Amherst community (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Writing class (excerpts from Conrad, Rilke, etc) (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Amherst student work (entrance essays) (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Amherst students: class work and correspondence (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Amherst students: class work and correspondence (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Writing class material: excerpts (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Writing class material: excerpts (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Olsen's reading list (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Radcliffe Institute: fellowships, papers, etc. (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Radcliffe Institute: fellowships, papers, etc. (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - Radcliffe Institute: fellowships, papers, etc. (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Radcliffe Institute: fellowships, papers, etc. (Box 44, Folder 14)
  - English 25: "Literature of Poverty" syllabus and notes (Box 44, Folder 15)
- Series 8. Awards and honors
  Series VIII contains articles, pamphlets, and degrees that pertain to the awards and honors Tillie Olsen received for her efforts as a writer and activist, including "Tillie Olsen Day" in San Francisco.
  - Honorary degrees, Tillie Olsen Week, etc. (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Honorary degrees, Tillie Olsen Week, etc. (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Honorary degrees, Tillie Olsen Week, etc. (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Honorary degrees, Tillie Olsen Week, etc. (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Honorary degrees, Tillie Olsen Week, etc. (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Honorary degrees, Tillie Olsen Week, etc. (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Honorary degrees, Tillie Olsen Week, etc. (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Honorary degrees, Tillie Olsen Week, etc. (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Honorary degrees, Tillie Olsen Week, etc. (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Honorary degrees, Tillie Olsen Week, etc. (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Degrees (Box 46)
- Series 9. Book reviews and book readings
  Series IX is made up entirely of pamphlets and announcements sent to Tillie Olsen regarding various book readings, book reviews, etc.
  - Pamphlets/Announcements (Box 47)
- Series 10. Miscellaneous
  Series X is the Miscellaneous section, consisting of various ephemera such as financial and legal papers, fragments of notes, teaching guides, catalogues, various writings, photographs, etc.
  - Artist's Liberation Front (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Utah Arts Council (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - American Writers Conference (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Request for Olsen's birth certificate (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Legal issues (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - "The Ess Coloring Book" (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Putney School Spring Conference, 1965 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous papers (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Dell College Paperbacks catalogues, 1983-84 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Virago Catalogues, 1979-1983 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Receipts; financial papers (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - "Schools & Mobility" (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Emily Carr miscellaneous (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Tell Me a Riddle teaching guides (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Midwestern Writer's Festival and Book Fair: excerpt from Tell Me a Riddle: signed copy 15 of 150 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Art ephemera (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - Feminist articles/writings (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Photographs: Rae, 1920's; English IX Class, ca., 1930's (Box 48, Folder 18)
- Series 11. Published works